MASOUD AKHGAR

Software Developer

my website

masoudmdar78@gmail.com

+33675565453

github.com/masoud-akhgar

Grenoble, France

in/masoudakhgar-ir

SUMMARY

I am Masoud Akhgar, graduated M2-Informatics, Mastered, motivated to constantly develop my skills and grow professionally, searching for Full-time CDI/CDD. Having not only experience and teamwork skills, but also an understanding of infrastructures - Chess Lover, committed to deadlines, Skating, Humourist, Hard-working, "No pain No gain"

SKILLS

Languages: Python(Django), C/C++, Java, HTML, Js, PHP(Laravel), SQL, PostgreSQL, SQlite

Libraries: OpenCV, NumPy, T-kinter,

Qml, Matplotlib, Pandas, Sklearn, bs4 ,pytorch,tensorflow,Jquery,bootstrap Git, Docker, CI/CD, Spark, GCP, Scrum

DevOps: Tools: Photoshop, Linux, Tableau, Excel, powerpoint,

EDUCATION

more than a year

Master M2 MOSIG Institut polytechnique de Grenoble - Ensimag

among 5th best universities in France

learn Principles and data management, plus novel ML models presented in recent years

9/2018 - 9/2022

Ferdowsi University of Mashhad

Ranked at top third universities in Iran

Teaching programming, software design, networks, database systems and AI systems, Specialized in one last year. I specialized on AI/Software development and did various projects with: GPU, CUDA, Trees, Java, Web, Cloud

EXPERIENCE

2/2023 - 9/2023 Cost Prediction - Data Scientist - more information

Schneider Electric - Grenoble Hub

- extimating final cost of plastic parts including hidden costs, using just just visible parts features
- · collecting data from all the world, and visualizing using Tableau and Excel
- · helping the company to reach out the error target
- · great achievement despite of small dataset, using XGBoost, sample weight learning, multi-models and NN, inspired by related paper SQL / Excel / python / Tableau / NN / optimization

1/2022 - 2/2022 Off-campus industrial project - Data/NLP Analyst - more information

- · Goal is information retrieval from platform, Classifying All Class Descriptions in Persian in Different Categories such as Sports, using a SQL database
- Scraping data from website, Preprocessing like remove stopwords, Using word2vec, Classflying words
- · Visualizing Outcome, query response services
- Worked with the Mizito platform based on Scrum bs4 / PostgreSQL / Django / clustering / Ру

12/2019 - 6/2021 Patent: Emg Signal Processor Application - Software Engineer - more information

Robotics Lab.

- Implemented Real-Time Signal Receiver and Plotter From Wireless And Serial Connection group of 12 people including electrical engineers and computer scientists, using Git, over 1.5 years
- Designed a Software in a Group with high Human Computer Interaction Using Qt, .ui and C++
- Familiar With Some Signal Filters Used In The Application C++ / Qt / Git / CI/CD / teamwork

6/2022 - 9/2021 Motion Intent Learning about Exoskeleton - AI Researcher/Intern - more information

- Robotics Lab.
- · Contributing research-based to a Wearable Sensing Systems Project For Motion Intent Learning
- Image-based Analysis papers, signal-driven learning models, RNN, LSTM and BDNN
- Mastered the process of Al-based Improvement in More Than 10 Recent Articles Using Deep Learning. signal-driven learning / recurrent networks / teamwork / image-processing

1/2021 - 5/2021 API-based Query Management (course) Project - more information

Ferdowsi university

- The goal is Query (Sqlite) management by having list of games, delivering project on cloud pipeline.
- It is responding to user through API by Json files, considering user's token
- Using Diango as backend + MVP model, and postman, so we dont provide GET/POST requests
- Building yml&docker, Creating artifacts and the pipeline on iranserver, deploying project API / Postman / Django-MVP / SQlite / Json / Docker / CI/CD

PUBLICATIONS AND DIPLOMAS

10/2021 - 7/2022 M. Akhgar, T. Bahraini, HS. Yazdi, "Robust Histogram of Oriented Gradient" - developer more information

- · Goal is producing robust HOG of image from a noisy one, using mathematical optimization
- Worked with image processing modules in python
- · Research-oriented & signal processing project leading to submit as a paper OpenCV / optimization / python / teamwork

9/2022 - in two weeks

Microsoft Azure Databricks for Data Engineering

more information/degree

Action, lazy and eager evaluations, Wide and Narrow transformations

 Processing streaming data with Azure Databricks structured streaming Key-Vault / CI/CD / Azure

Databricks / Sparks /

6/2020 - 9/2020 ACM-contest Participation

Focusing on dynamic programming, solving more than hundred problems on codeforces

C++ / DP

REFERENCES -

Slimane Merabti Vice President Industrialization FD IEC - Schneider Electric
 Email: slimane.merabti@se.com
 Please don't hesitate to ask any **proof** of mentioned data, or contact the references.

English - C1, French - B1/B2 (able to communicate)